# Danyang Zhuo

Assistant Professor Department of Computer Science Trinity College of Arts and Sciences Duke University January 12, 2021 308 Research Dr Durham, NC 27705 danyang@cs.duke.edu https://danyangzhuo.com

# **Research Interests**

I do research broadly in computer systems, including operating systems, distributed systems, and computer networks, with a focus on the design and implementation of data center systems to support today's increasingly data-intensive applications (e.g., deep learning, big data analytics, packet processing). My approaches include software architecture design, programming languages, and machine learning.

# **Education**

University of Washington - Seattle

Seattle, Washington

Ph.D. in Computer Science and Engineering

Sep 2013 - Aug 2019

- Dissertation: Practical, Efficient, and Reliable Data Center Communication.
- Advisors: Thomas E. Anderson, Arvind Krishnamurthy

University of Illinois - Urbana Champaign

B.S. in Electrical Engineering

Urbana, Illinois Aug 2009 - May 2013

Advisor: Nitin Vaidya

## **Professional Experience**

Duke University					
Assistant	Professor	of	Computer	Science	

University of California – Berkeley

 $Postdoctoral\ Researcher$ 

- Advisor: Ion Stoica

Microsoft Research

Contractor (through Populous Group)

Microsoft Research

Research Intern

Google

Software Development Engineering Intern

Amazon

Software Development Engineering Intern

Microsoft

Software Development Engineering Intern

Durham, North Carolina Jul 2020 - now

Berkeley, California Sep 2019 - Jun 2020

Redmond, Washington Oct 2015 - Feb 2017

Redmond, Washington Jun 2015 - Sep 2015

Mountain View, California

Sep 2014 - Mar 2015

Seattle, Washington May 2013 - Sep 2013

Redmond, Washington

May 2012 - Aug 2012

## **Publications**

# Conference Papers

- 1. Sitan Chen, Xiaoxiao Li, Zhao Song, **Danyang Zhuo**. On InstaHide, Phase Retrieval, and Sparse Matrix Factorization. The 9th International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR), 2021.
- 2. Samantha Miller, Kaiyuan Zhang, Mengqi Chen, Ryan Jennings, Ang Chen, **Danyang Zhuo**, Thomas Anderson. *High Velocity Kernel File Systems with Bento*. The 19th USENIX Conference on File and Storage Technologies (FAST), 2021.
- 3. Lianmin Zheng, Chengfan Jia, Minmin Sun, Zhao Wu, Cody Hao Yu, Ameer Haj-Ali, Yida Wang, Jun Yang, **Danyang Zhuo**, Koushik Sen, Joseph E. Gonzalez, Ion Stoica. *Ansor: Generating High-Performance Tensor Programs for Deep Learning*. The 14th USENIX Symposium on Operating Systems Design and Implementation (OSDI), 2020.
- Kaiyuan Zhang, Danyang Zhuo, Arvind Krishnamurthy. Gallium: Automated Software Middlebox Offloading to Programmable Switches. In Proceedings of the Conference of the ACM Special Interest Group on Data Communication (SIGCOMM), 2020.
- 5. Kaiyuan Zhang, **Danyang Zhuo**, Aditya Akella, Arvind Krishnamurthy, Xi Wang. *Automated Verification of Customizable Middlebox Properties with Gravel*. The 17th USENIX Symposium on Networked Systems Design and Implementation (NSDI), 2020.
- Danyang Zhuo, Kaiyuan Zhang, Yibo Zhu, Hongqiang Harry Liu, Matthew Rockett, Arvind Krishnamurthy, Thomas Anderson. Slim: OS Kernel Support for a Low-Overhead Container Overlay Network. The 16th USENIX Symposium on Networked Systems Design and Implementation (NSDI), 2019.
- Danyang Zhuo, Monia Ghobadi, Ratul Mahajan, Klaus-Tycho Förster, Arvind Krishnamurthy and Thomas E. Anderson. *Understanding and Mitigating Packet Corruption in Data Center* Networks. In Proceedings of the Conference of the ACM Special Interest Group on Data Communication (SIGCOMM), 2017.
- 8. **Danyang Zhuo**, Monia Ghobadi, Ratul Mahajan, Amar Phanishayee, Xuan Kelvin Zou, Hang Guan, Arvind Krishnamurthy and Thomas E. Anderson. *RAIL: A Case for Redundant Arrays of Inexpensive Links in Data Center Networks*. The 14th USENIX Symposium on Networked Systems Design and Implementation (NSDI), 2017.
- 9. Vincent Liu, **Danyang Zhuo**, Simon Peter, Arvind Krishnamurthy and Thomas E. Anderson. Subways: A Case for Redundant, Inexpensive Data Center Edge Links. The 13th International Conference on emerging Networking EXperiments and Technologies (CoNEXT), 2015.

#### Workshop Papers

- Samantha Miller, Kaiyuan Zhang, Danyang Zhuo, Shibin Xu, Arvind Krishnamurthy, Thomas Anderson. Practical Safe Linux Kernel Extensibility. The 17th Workshop on Hot Topics in Operating Systems (HotOS), 2019.
- 2. **Danyang Zhuo**, Qiao Zhang, Xin Yang, Vincent Liu. *Canaries in the Network*. The 15th ACM Workshop on Hot Topics in Networks (HotNets), 2016.

- 3. **Danyang Zhuo**, Qiao Zhang, Vincent Liu, Arvind Krishnamurthy, Thomas E. Anderson. *Rack-level Congestion Control*. The 15th ACM Workshop on Hot Topics in Networks (HotNets), 2016.
- 4. **Danyang Zhuo**, Qiao Zhang, Dan Ports, Arvind Krishnamurthy, Thomas E. Anderson. *Machine Fault Tolerance for Reliable Datacenter Systems*. The 5th Asia-Pacific Workshop on Systems (APSys), 2014.

#### **Patents**

1. Monia Ghobadi, Ratul Mahajan, Amar Phanishayee, **Danyang Zhuo**, Xuan Kelvin Zou. *Data Center Topology Having Multiple Classes of Reliability*. US Patent 20170302565A1. WIPO Patent 2017180450A1.

## **Students**

#### Current PhD Students

Jingrong Chen (2020-), Guozhen She (2020-), Xinhao Kong (2021-)

## **Awards**

University of Washington Madrona Prize Runner-Up	2018
University of Washington Hacherl Endowed Fellowship	2014
Rank 146th in the William Lowell Putnam Mathematical Competition	2012

#### **Invited Talk**

- ACM SIGCOMM

•	Towards	Efficient	and	Reliable	Data	Center	Systems.
---	---------	-----------	-----	----------	------	--------	----------

v					
- Yale University	Apr 2019				
- Purdue University	Apr 2019				
- University of Virginia	Mar 2019				
- Duke University	Mar 2019				
- Rutgers University	Mar 2019				
- Microsoft Research	Mar 2019				
- Penn State University	Feb 2019				
- University of Minnesota	Feb 2019				
• Slim: OS Kernel Support for a Low-Overhead Container Overlay Network.					
- Princeton University	Jun 2020				
- USENIX NSDI	Feb 2019				
• Understanding and Mitigating Packet Corruption in Data Center Networks.					

• RAIL: A Case for Redundant Arrays of Inexpensive Links in Data Center Ne	etworks.				
- USENIX NSDI	Mar 2017				
Teaching					
• CPS 510: Advanced Operating Systems. (Fall 2020)					

Service

Program Committee

• SIGCOMM (2020)